<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy 463: Intro Metaphysics</title>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/463/syllabus.rss</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <generator>blosxom/2.1.2</generator>

  <item>
    <title>Syllabus: Philosophy 463</title>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/463/2010/02/01#syllabus</link>
    <category></category>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://davidsanson.com/463/syllabus</guid>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Winter 2010, MW 12:30PM - 2:18PM, University Hall 0086&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://davidsanson.com/463&quot;&gt;http://davidsanson.com/463&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Sanson&lt;br /&gt;University Hall 372&lt;br /&gt;Office Hours: M 2:30&amp;ndash;3:30; W 11:30&amp;ndash;12:30, or by appointment&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
&lt;!--
h=&apos;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x75;&amp;#46;&amp;#x65;&amp;#100;&amp;#x75;&apos;;a=&apos;&amp;#64;&apos;;n=&apos;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x61;&amp;#110;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#110;&amp;#46;&amp;#x37;&apos;;e=n+a+h;
document.write(&apos;&lt;a h&apos;+&apos;ref&apos;+&apos;=&quot;ma&apos;+&apos;ilto&apos;+&apos;:&apos;+e+&apos;&quot;&gt;&apos;+&apos;&lt;code&gt;&apos;+e+&apos;&lt;/code&gt;&apos;+&apos;&lt;\/&apos;+&apos;a&apos;+&apos;&gt;&apos;);
// --&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x61;&amp;#110;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#110;&amp;#46;&amp;#x37;&amp;#32;&amp;#x61;&amp;#116;&amp;#32;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x75;&amp;#32;&amp;#100;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#116;&amp;#32;&amp;#x65;&amp;#100;&amp;#x75;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;course-description&quot;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to some problems in contemporary metaphysics: the problem of nonexistent objects; the problem of universals; the problem of bare particulars; McTaggart&amp;rsquo;s paradox and the passage of time; the problem of change; the problem of possible worlds; and the problem of transworld identity. These problems all share a common theme: what, if anything, can we say about the fundamental structure and nature of reality?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;textbook&quot;&gt;Textbook&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Peter van Inwagen and Dean Zimmerman (eds), &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics: The Big Questions&lt;/em&gt;, Second Edition. Blackwell, 2008. ISBN: 9781405125864&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the articles in the textbook are available online in other forms. I encourage you to buy the textbook: it is a &lt;em&gt;very good&lt;/em&gt; collection and you would do well to work through it all, even the parts we don&amp;rsquo;t cover in class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your grade will be based upon two essays, a final exam, occasional exercises, and class participation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First Essay: 20%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Second Essay: 30%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Final Exam: 30%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exercises: 10%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Participation: 10%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first essay will be shorter than the second; the second will be no more than 5 pages. The final exam is on Tuesday of Finals week (Mar 16th) from 11:30&amp;mdash;1:18. No, you can&amp;rsquo;t take the exam early because your (brother is getting married/family is going to Europe, etc.) and you need to blow town. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Participting is not identical to attending. Come to class prepared to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;academic-misconduct&quot;&gt;Academic Misconduct&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, I want to emphasize that you are strongly encouraged to discuss the course material with your peers&amp;mdash;philosophical conversation is one of the best ways to get better at doing philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is your responsibility to know what counts as academic misconduct. Your work &lt;strong&gt;must be your own work&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;all sources must be cited&lt;/strong&gt;. I will report offenders to the Committee on Academic Misconduct (COAM). If you are confused, or need more guidance, ask. If you have not already, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://oaa.osu.edu/coam/faq&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://oaa.osu.edu/coam/faq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;disabilities&quot;&gt;Disabilities&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you need (or may need) an accommodation based on the impact of a disability, please contact me now, not later. I will work with the Office for Disability Services to coordinate reasonable accommodations for any student with a documented disability. Office for Disability Services, 150 Pomerene Hall, 292&amp;ndash;3307, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ods.ohio-state.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.ods.ohio-state.edu/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;email&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email is the best way to reach me. However, I am not always online. Please allow me 48 hours to respond. If I have not responded in 48 hours please email me again, letting me know it is your second email (I won&amp;rsquo;t take this as harassment). Always include &amp;ldquo;463&amp;rdquo; in the subject line of your email.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
