<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Phil863: Metaphysics Seminar</title>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/863/old/863blurb.rss</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <generator>blosxom/2.1.2</generator>

  <item>
    <title>Phil 863: Graduate Seminar in Metaphysics</title>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 21:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/863/2010/02/01#863blurb</link>
    <category>/old</category>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://davidsanson.com/863/old/863blurb</guid>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent works by Kit Fine and Ted Sider aim to carve out a distinctively metaphysical approach to issues in meta-metaphysics. According to Fine, metaphysicians are not interested in ordinary facts, but in the facts that constitute reality; less metaphorically, they are interested what is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; the case, not just what is the case. According to Sider, metaphysicians aim to uncover the structure of reality&amp;mdash;the fundamental metaphysical joints&amp;mdash;and, Sider argues, metaphysicians should take seriously the possibility that reality has not just predicational joints (i.e., fundamental properties), but also quantificational joints, logical joints, tense-operator joints, or modal-operator joints. Both Fine and Sider are reacting against a variety of anti-metaphysical approaches to issues in meta-metaphysics, approaches motivated in part by skepticism concerning any putative distinction between what is the case and what is really the case and by skepticism concerning the idea that reality has a fundamental structure. The aim of this seminar is to assess the plausibility and commitments of metaphysical approaches to meta-metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will read works by Fine and Sider; we will likely read works by at least some of Goodman, Dummett, Lewis, Hirsch, MacFarlane, Haslanger, Hawthorne, Schaeffer, Bennett, Eklund, and Dorr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email me for more information and suggested background reading.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
