<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Phil863: Metaphysics Seminar</title>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/863/old/originalblurb.rss</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <generator>blosxom/2.1.2</generator>

  <item>
    <title>Phil 863: Graduate Seminar in Metaphysics</title>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 21:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <link>http://davidsanson.com/863/2010/02/01#originalblurb</link>
    <category>/old</category>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://davidsanson.com/863/old/originalblurb</guid>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;For awhile, I was planning a seminar on metametaphysics, and, in particular, on recent work by Fine and Sider attempting to describe and motivate the metametaphysical commitments of dogmatic metaphysics: for Fine, a commitment to a distinction between what is the case and what is really the case; for Sider, a commitment to metaphysical &amp;ldquo;joints&amp;rdquo; in the world. The aim of the course was to figure out what we dogmatists can say in response to deflationists, relativists, quietists, and their ilk, and consider whether it was a comfortable thing to say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was going to be the case, but it will not be (and so never would be) the case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The seminar will instead be on the metaphysics of tense. There are two clusters of issues that fall under this broad heading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first cluster has to do with a traditional distinction between tensed and tenseless sentences, statements, propositions, and facts. A tensed sentence, statement, or proposition is one that changes its truth value with time; a tenseless one does not. So &amp;lsquo;David is sitting&amp;rsquo; is (plausibly) tensed, while &amp;lsquo;David is sitting at 5 pm on October 20th, 2009&amp;rsquo; is not. We&amp;rsquo;ll have occasion to worry about tensed sentences, statements, and propositions, but our real interest will be in tensed facts. A tensed fact is an impermanent fact: the kind of fact that, when it is around, makes a tensed proposition true. Metaphysicians worry about whether or not there are any tensed facts, or whether or not there is any genuine dispute to be had on the issue. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think there are tensed facts, and there is a real dispute to be had on this issue. We will consider the issues raised by this problem, including recent work by Fine and Sider attempting to describe and motivate the commitments of the person who says that there is a genuine dispute to be had on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second cluster has to do with the past and future. Tensed facts, if there are any, are temporary. This gives rise to a contrast between what facts there are, what facts there were, and what facts there will be. But how can we understand this contrast? In terms of there being more temporary facts? I suspect that won&amp;rsquo;t work. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, are we forced to give up on the (disreputable) idea that the world is constituted by facts? Are we committed to truths that are not grounded in what facts there are? How does this relate to the more general question of how to understand the difference between past and future? Does it connect up with the view that the past somehow fixed or necessary or determinate in a way that the future is not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Those familiar with tense logic might recast the issues at the core of these two clusters as follows: (1) Should we take tense logic&amp;mdash;a logic whose atomic sentences are interpreted as tensed rather than tenseless&amp;mdash;to be a guide to reality (and does that question make sense)? (2) If we do take tense logic as a guide to reality, what about the world is being conveyed by our use of tense operators (and what is the logic of those operators)?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will be reading stuff by McTaggart, Broad, Prior, Dummett, Geach, Massey, Lewis, Mellor, Haslanger, Fine, Sider, Hinchliff, Williamson, and Zimmerman, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the metametaphysical themes that stood at the center of the course that was going to occur will also arise within the course that will occur, and will be discussed and taken seriously. They will arise, however, in the context of a particular issue&amp;mdash;tense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email me (sanson.7@osu.edu) for more information and suggested background reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The seminar will meet Tuesdays, from 3:30&amp;ndash;6:18, in the seminar room.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
